[Music]
Hello, I'm Mariana, and I'm
independent from Mac's civil transport personnel
and I'm here to talk a little about the
proposed revision of ribata 61, which
deals with the possibility of extending the
type qualification for pilots operating
in general transport, this initiative was
conceived with the simple flight program that
aims to simplify unlocking
and reduce the costs of the Claro sector without
sacrificing operational safety this
proposal was made considering the
principles of responsive regulation and
Risk Management the current rule establishes
a pilot Maintained the validity of its
type qualification he needs to undergo
training and an example of proficiency
every 12 months what the proposal brings
then is the possibility of extending
this period to 24 months subject to
some conditions So these conditions
are that he operates in general creation and that
he has a lot of experience including
experience in that type of aircraft
and constantly maintain your awareness That
is the
recent difference in the interrupta
so an objective of collecting the
contributions of the entire ANAC sector is
opening a new public consultation is
available on our website and we will
also hold a public hearing on the
30th of May in a hybrid face-to-
face format in Brasilia and online which
better explain the proposal and allow
everyone to make their contributions through the
form that is on our website so I
invite you all to participate
in these moments of consultation and audience
to make your contributions because this
is very important for the maturing
of the regulation and our
regulatory process it is also important to point out
other initiatives that Natu has been
studying to seek to expand the
simulator park in Brazil including the
possibility of using the Airway fund
country
training offer for the most
representative aircraft in general aviation So
these two measures complement each other, the
latter being more comprehensive in terms
of the amount impacted and both focus on
reducing training and
qualification courses for pilots and
general transport as a whole
[Music]